

# **Askar Ibn Azad**Sr. Software Engineer (Remote) at Royex Technology

L+880 1751242425 | Sakaribn223@gmail.com

#### **Profile**

Experienced in developing and maintaining large scale applications like Banking Solution, Project Management Solution, HRM Solution, ZKTeco Attendance Solution. Have a good understanding and working experience with web application development, debugging, bug fixing. Working with technologies like .Net Core, React, MSSQL, Oracle, Javascript. Solved 600+ algorithmic problems on online platforms.

#### **Experiences**

## Royex Technology - Dubai, UAE - Remote

#### Sr Software Engineer - January 2024 to Present

Responsibility is to Develop and maintain their existing software product HRM, ZKTeco Attendance, Land Management System using the latest cutting edge technology. As working in a small team my regular tasks include Designing database, code as Full-Stack, Provide Client Support, Bug fixing, Designing report.

# Pixamatics Technology - Banani, Dhaka

#### **Software Engineer - June 2022 to December 2023**

Responsibility is to Develop and maintain their existing software product HRM, ZKTeco Attendance, Land Management System using the latest cutting edge technology. As working in a small team my regular tasks include Designing database, code as Full-Stack, Provide Client Support, Bug fixing, Designing report.

#### PC Link IT - Mohammadpur, Dhaka

#### Software Developer - November 2021 to May 2022

Responsibility is to Develop and maintain their existing software product Microfin Anirban ERP (Microfinance Banking Solution), Anirban Helpdesk (Project Management Software) as Full Stack. Analyze Client requirements, design database architecture and develop software systems.

#### **Junior Software Developer - December 2020 to October 2021**

Practicing and Implementing Full stack Development, Conduct Manual testing using Gray-Box and White Box Methodology. Designing lubricating Crystal Reports. Writing documentation and user manuals for their software clients as well as internal stuff.

#### **Projects**

#### ■ Microfin Anirban ERP (Microfinance Banking Solution)

- Recently Involved in the development and maintenance process
- It is considered as One of the most popular microfinance software in Bangladesh
- 70+ Clients (NGO and CoOperatives)
- 700+ Branches
- Technologies: .NET 4.5, MVC 4, Oracle 12g, SAP Crystal Report, Javascript, Kendo UI

#### ■ Anirban Helpdesk (Project Management Software) - Project Leader

- My responsibility was to Analyze requirements, Design Database Architecture and Develop Application
  patterns. I used to Assign tasks to the team and monitor the workflow.
- 6 types (Client, Operation, DevOps, Developer, DBA, Management) of users.
- Clients can through Software issues or future requirements to the Operation team.
- Every user can create and assign tasks to another user according to hierarchy
- Setting priority, timeline and keeping track of assigned task are so simple
- Almost 5000+ Client users putting their issues on a daily basis
- Technologies: .NET 4.5, MVC 4, Oracle 12g, SAP Crystal Report, Javascript, Kendo UI

#### ■ Human Resource Management

- Currently Involved in the development team using the latest technology
- Technologies: .NET CORE, React, RDLC report, SQL Server

#### **Accomplishments**

#### Codeforces

Solved 500+ Algorithmic problems related to [Implementation, Sorting, Array Manipulation, Brute Forces, Math]

#### HackerRank Certified Skills

- Certificate on Problem Solving (Basic + Intermediate).
- Certificate on SQL (Basic + Intermediate + Advanced)

#### **Familiar Technologies**



### **Education**

- American International University Bangladesh. 408/1, Kuratoli, Dhaka 1229 Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering 2017. CGPA 3.54 out of 4.00
- **Notre Dame College Mymensingh.** City Bypass, Barera, Mymensingh HSC-2016. GPA 4.83 out of 5.00
- **Anjuman Adarsha Government High School**. Muktarpara,Netrokona SSC-2014. GPA 5.00 out of 5.00